bunches.co.uk 2018-08-19

# Terms and Conditions, Privacy, and Cookie Policy | Bunches

Bunches Florapost Ltd are completely dedicated to your total satisfaction.

If you have any suggestions or comments regarding our flowers please email us at [flowers@bunches.co.uk](mailto:flowers@bunches.co.uk).

### Our Contact Details:

Bunches Florapost Ltd  
19 Hazelford Way  
Newstead Village  
Nottinghamshire  
United Kingdom  
NG15 0DQ 

**Freephone:**[0800 626 249](tel:0800626249)  
 **From outside UK:**[+44 1623 750343](tel:+441623750343)  
 **Fax:** 01623 758704  
 **Email:**[flowers@bunches.co.uk](mailto:flowers@bunches.co.uk)

Registered in England and Wales. Company registration number: _3924234_  
VAT registration number: _509377820_  
Data Protection Act registration number _Z4831682_  
All prices include VAT at the relevant rate. 

### Making A Purchase

This site has been designed to make ordering flowers in the Bunches Florapost range as easy and convenient as possible. Simply select your choice of bouquet, click on the 'Place Order' button, proceed to checkout, fill in your details and leave the rest to us. Your beautifully boxed flowers and gifts will be sent by guaranteed courier or Royal Mail first class post to any address in the UK - 6 days a week. We can take orders weeks and months in advance on our sophisticated ordering system.

### General Delivery Information For All Orders

  * We can deliver to any postal address in the UK. We only deliver within the UK and we do not deliver to Europe or the Republic of Ireland.
  * Our 26 years of experience shows that over 97% of deliveries arrive the next working day.
  * Please note **we cannot offer same day delivery**.
  * When ordering please enter the full address including the postcode of the recipient. **We will not be held responsible for items that are not delivered due to incorrect details.**
  * We do not pass on any details and the only information sent with the gift is the personal message card.
  * Should the recipient be away at the time of delivery, a card will be left stating attempted delivery and will include details of how to collect them or arrange re-delivery.
  * Please note - We do not include a vase with any of our bouquets as standard. Bouquets are pictured in a vase on the website for display purposes, but a vase is not shipped with any bouquet unless one is added as as optional extra in the checkout.
  * Flowers sent to hospitals, schools, military & business addresses will be delivered to a main reception or mailing room prior to internal distribution. We recommend that orders to such locations be requested for delivery on a weekday and not Saturday.
  * There are no deliveries on Sundays or Bank Holidays.

### Delivery Information For Flower and Balloon Gifts

  * All items include delivery by Royal Mail First Class Post unless stated otherwise. Please allow 1-2 working days for delivery.
  * We usually despatch flowers one day prior to the delivery date requested.
  * As we deliver by First Class Royal Mail we cannot deliver on Sunday or Bank Holidays.
  * Deliveries can take place up to 6:00pm Monday to Friday and up to 1:00pm on Saturday.

### Optional Courier Delivery Details

  * For an additional fee of £5.99 we offer a guaranteed delivery on the day of your choice between 8:00am and 6:00pm.
  * Flowers delivered by this service will need to be signed for by the recipient.
  * For an extra £7.99 you can guarantee delivery for before 1:00pm on the day of your choice.
  * For next working day deliveries, orders must be placed before 6:00pm.

### Credit Card Security

Bunches Florapost accept payment from all major credit and debit cards, including Visa, Mastercard, Switch/Maestro, American Express, Visa Electron, Delta, Eurocard, and JCB. We also accept payment by PayPal.

This site uses Sagepay, Braintree (PayPal), and WorldPay for online credit card transactions. These are the most popular online payment systems in the UK. All payment information is transmitted in secure mode and is encrypted using the highest levels of online security encryption available. Firewalls within the Sagepay system prevent any unauthorised access to your information. Credit card details are captured within the systems of the payment providers, and no card details are stored on your computer or computers belonging to Bunches Florapost. When your order has been placed, you will receive an email from Bunches to confirm the payment has been successful.

### Substitution Policy

In the unlikely event of supply difficulties, Bunches Florapost Ltd reserves the right to substitute any product with any other type of equal quality and value.

### Returns Policy And Cancellation Rights

If you are in any way disappointed with our flowers or service, please telephone us on freephone [0800 626 249](tel:0800626249) or [(+44) 1623 750343](tel:+441623750343), or email us at [flowers@bunches.co.uk](mailto:flowers@bunches.co.uk). Alternatively you can write to us at: 

Bunches Florapost Ltd  
19 Hazelford Way  
Newstead Village  
Nottinghamshire  
NG15 0DQ 

  * If you have cause for complaint this must be received within 14 days after despatch. Please note we cannot guarantee an exact delivery date on flowers dispatched by first class post.
  * Our customer service phone line is personally operated between 9:00am and 5:30pm Monday to Friday and 9.00am to 12:00pm Saturday. This may be extended during busier times.
  * All calls are charged at the national rate.
  * We aim to respond to customer service matters within one working day and resolve all complaints within three working days. Calls may be monitored for training purposes and to maintain our high level of quality service.

In accordance with the _Consumer Contracts Regulations (2013)_ you may also cancel your order at any time without reason, within 14 working days of delivery. Should you wish to cancel your order and receive a refund, you must confirm this in writing within 14 working days of receipt and return the packaged item to us at the address given above. 

The item(s) must be returned to us unused and in as new condition. You will be liable for all postage costs incurred as a result of returning an item to us. We cannot issue a refund until we have received the goods. We recommend you obtain proof of posting when you return any goods to us. 

Please note this policy excludes all our flower products as these are perishable goods and exempt from this legislation. This does not affect your statutory rights as a consumer. 

### Website Disclaimer

The information contained in this website is for general information purposes only. The information is provided by Bunches Florapost Limited and while we endeavour to keep the information up to date and correct, we make no representations or warranties of any kind, express or implied, about the completeness, accuracy, reliability, suitability or availability with respect to the website or the information, products, services, or related graphics contained on the website for any purpose. Any reliance you place on such information is therefore strictly at your own risk. 

In no event will we be liable for any loss or damage including without limitation, indirect or consequential loss or damage, or any loss or damage whatsoever arising from loss of data or profits arising out of, or in connection with, the use of this website. 

Through this website you are able to link to other websites which are not under the control of Bunches Florapost Limited. We have no control over the nature, content and availability of those sites. The inclusion of any links does not necessarily imply a recommendation or endorse the views expressed within them. 

Every effort is made to keep the website up and running smoothly. However, Bunches Florapost Limited takes no responsibility for, and will not be liable for, the website being temporarily unavailable due to technical issues beyond our control. 

### SSAFA, the Armed Forces Charity

For those customers who visit Bunches.co.uk via SSAFA, the Armed Forces Charity website, Bunches.co.uk will donate 12% of the order total to SSAFA in support of the charity. 

For our hampers, we have the following additional and amended terms. 

  * All hampers exclude delivery.
  * Hamper delivery will be charged at £6.50.
  * The following postcodes will incur an additional charge to the standard £6.50 and delivery to these postcodes can take up to 48 hours: 
    * **AB, IV, KW, PA, PH, BT, HS, KA, and IM.**
  * Unfortunately we cannot deliver hampers to the following postcodes: 
    * **GY, JE, TR21 - TR25, and ZE.**
  * Hampers will be delivered by courier on your chosen day between Monday and Friday.
  * There are no deliveries on Saturday, Sunday, or bank holidays.
  * We cannot deliver hampers on the same day of ordering. Orders placed before 1:00pm can be dispatched same day for delivery at the earliest available date.
  * All hampers will have to be signed for and if the recipient is out then a card will be left with instructions to contact the courier.
  * We do not deliver outside the UK.
  * We cannot deliver to PO boxes or BFPO addresses.

Here at Bunches, we understand how important your personal data is. We have and always will be committed to protecting your information, and we do this in compliance with both the Data Protection Act and GDPR.

To Deliver Happiness...

We will only ever use your data to process your order, to contact you regarding the order and to keep you up to date with useful product information and offers. We simply wish to provide you with the best possible service and we only use the necessary data to deliver happiness for you on every occasion.

You're in Control...

If you want us to keep in touch, we will. If not, that's no problem. If you ever want to unsubscribe - this can be done by simply clicking 'unsubscribe' on any of our emails or via your online Bunches account under 'edit your details'. Alternatively, you can email us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Rest Assured...

We store all your personal data securely, and we won't hang onto your data any longer than needs be.

Simple and Straightforward ...

We don't hide behind complex legal terms so if you have any questions regarding our privacy policy, we have our own data protection officer on site available to answer any queries you may have.

We are here for **you** and will look after your personal data.

Click here to read our full Privacy Policy

#### How we use your data and why:

  1. Name and contact details of you and recipients

    * To deliver your gifts for you - we need this information to complete your order.
    * To keep in touch - if needs be - with regards to your order, providing you with the best possible service.
    * To keep you up to date on new ranges, our latest gifts and discounts - unless of course, you choose not to be included on our mailing lists.
    * To detect and prevent any potential fraudulent activity - this is important to us, as we wish to safeguard your data to the highest possible degree.
  2. Your payment information

    * To take payment or refund you. We can't uphold our contract with you without this information! However, we do not store your card details. If you choose to store your card details on your online Bunches account, or you have a current subscription with us, they will be stored with our secure payment provider under contract with ourselves in compliance with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS).
    * To detect and prevent any potential fraudulent activity.
  3. Your order history

    * To provide you with the best possible customer care and support - our customer support team need this information to help you with any order queries, complaints and thank-yous!
    * We also use your order history for our reports to continue to try and provide you with the best products and service.
  4. How you use our website

    * To improve your overall experience, we use a web analytics function. This records device data i.e. whether you are visiting our site using a computer, phone or tablet; what operating system or browser this employs; as well as device model. It also enables us to see what pages you have visited and where you've clicked, this is performed through the use of cookies. We use this information solely to improve your experience on our website. Please note this information is completely anonymous.
  5. Your responses to competitions, promotions and surveys

    * We need this information to carry out our contract with you! - Without this information you wouldn't be able to enter competitions or receive promotions from us.

You are not obliged to provide us with your personal information, however if you don't you may not be able to complete your purchase with us. This may also impact your overall customer experience. But, this is your choice and we will always respect your decision.

#### Sharing your information

We value your data and would therefore never sell your data to any third party. This includes all information you provide us with. We simply aim to earn your trust and maintain this throughout our consumer-customer relationship. At Bunches we are like a family, and with many of our staff also being customers too, we all understand the importance of trust and privacy.

In the process of fulfilling your order or marketing requests we do pass your data onto the following parties:

  * Delivery companies including Royal Mail, Royal Mail Special Delivery, DPD and DPD Local.
  * Our payment service providers Braintree and Sagepay.
  * Our marketing distribution companies.

#### Marketing messages

If you have purchased with us within the last 36 months we will keep you up to date with marketing materials by email or post, unless you have otherwise stated that you do not wish to receive these. After this period, we will contact you to ask if you would like to remain on our mailing lists, and as always this is your decision and we will respect that. We do this as you have expressed an interest in our products and we like to warmly welcome you to the Bunches family.

You can stop marketing materials being sent at any time.

You can do so…

  * Via your online Bunches account under 'edit your details'.
  * By clicking 'unsubscribe' at the bottom of any one of our emails.
  * Or by contacting our customer support team by email at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#deb8b2b1a9bbacad9ebcabb0bdb6bbadf0bdb1f0abb5), or alternatively by phone on 0800 626 249.

Once you have unsubscribed, this will be actioned within 7 days.

Stopping marketing messages will not stop order confirmation emails and order updates from being received.

If you wish to amend any of your account details, this can be done…

  * Via your online Bunches account under 'edit your details'.
  * Or by contacting our customer support team by email at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#dabcb6b5adbfa8a99ab8afb4b9b2bfa9f4b9b5f4afb1), or alternatively by phone on 0800 626 249.

Any amendments will be actioned immediately on your account but may take up to 7 days for updates to be made to our mailing lists.

#### Keeping your information

We will hold your data for as long as you have an account with us; if you don't order with us for 36 months or more, we will contact you to let you know we will no longer be keeping in touch, but we will still keep your account in case you ever want to come back! If you still wish to hear from us this can be updated at any point by contacting our customer support team by email at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#cea8a2a1b9abbcbd8eacbba0ada6abbde0ada1e0bba5), or alternatively by phone on 0800 626 249.

If you don't have an account with us and use our guest checkout feature, we will hold your data for as long as we may need to be able to provide you with the highest degree of customer care.

We keep records of your orders and account to meet legal requirements, as well as for reporting purposes.

If you wish for us to anonymise your account, we can. Upon anonymisation the account would have no indication that it had once belonged to you.

#### Your rights

Here at Bunches we believe that it is of great importance that you are aware of your rights and have the amenities by which to exercise them.

  * The right to access your personal data held by us.
  * The right to be informed about how we use your personal data.
  * The right to request any incorrect data to be rectified - this can be done via your online account or alternatively by contacting our customer support team.
  * The right to request that we cease processing your data.
  * The right to request that we anonymise your data.
  * The right to stop direct marketing messages - this can be done via your online account, by clicking unsubscribe at the bottom of any marketing email or alternatively by contacting our customer support team.
  * The right to request your data to be transferred to either yourself or another service provider.
  * The right to withdraw consent.
  * The right to file a complaint with the Data Protection Regulator - in the UK this is the Information Commissioner's Office. Details of how to contact them can be found at ICO.org.uk.

If you wish to exercise any of your rights, or have any questions, our Data Protection officer will be more than happy to help. Please send any queries to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#3a5e5b4e5b4a48554e5f594e5355547a584f5459525f49145955144f51), or alternatively you can ask to speak to our data protection officer on 0800 626 249.

#### Updates to this notice

This information is subject to change as we often review how we process your data.

If there are any significant alterations made, we will contact you via email or post.

This notice was last updated on the 18/05/2018.

### Visitors to our Website

When someone visits [www.bunches.co.uk](https://www.bunches.co.uk/) we collect standard Internet log information and details of visitor behaviour patterns. We do this to find out things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of the site. 

### Use of Cookies

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site. 

The table below explains the cookies we use and why.

Cookie| Name| Purpose| More Information  
---|---|---|---  
PHP Session| PHPSESSID| This cookie is used to maintain your session with Bunches.co.uk allowing you to place orders.|   
Bunches.co.uk login details| email  
password| These cookies are optional. They are created when ticking the "remember me" box when logging in. They allow for Bunches.co.uk to remember your login details. The password cookie is encrypted to ensure your password is safe.|    
Google Analytics| 

  * _utma
  * _utmb
  * _utmc
  * _utmz
  * _atuvc

| These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited.| [Click here for an overview of privacy at Google](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html)  
Criteo| 

  * uid
  * uic
  * udc
  * udi
  * dis

| These cookies are used to allow us to produce personalised marketing in an **anonymous** manner on partner websites. You can opt out of Criteo cookies on their [privacy policy page](http://www.criteo.com/us/privacy-policy).| [Click here for an overview of privacy at Criteo and/or opt out.](https://www.criteo.com/us/privacy-policy)  
  
Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

### YouTube Cookies

We embed videos from our official YouTube channel using YouTube's privacy-enhanced mode. This mode may set cookies on your computer once you click on the YouTube video player, but YouTube will not store personally-identifiable cookie information for playbacks of embedded videos using the privacy-enhanced mode.

### Payment Cookies

 _Sagepay_ and _Braintree_ use cookies to store session details when handling payments. You can read more about their cookie and privacy policies at the following links: [Sagepay Privacy Policy](http://www.sagepay.com/privacy_policy), [Braintree (PayPal Inc.) Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/uk/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full). 

#### Flower Press

##### Flower Press Competition

  * Competition opens Thursday 16th August 2018 and the closing date for entries is midnight Friday 24th August 2018.
  * Prize: 3 winners will be selected at random from the correct entries and will receive a Sweet Violet bouquet and a gift box of 3 Belvoir Cordials. No cash alternative available and the prize is non-transferable.
  * Competitions and prize draws are open to everyone aged 18 and over (excluding employees of Bunches Florapost Ltd, their families or anyone else associated with the promotion).
  * Entries must be original and they must not copy the work of someone else.
  * Only one entry per person. Entries made on behalf of another person will not be accepted and joint submissions are not allowed.
  * Prize can only be delivered to addresses within the UK.
  * The winners will be chosen randomly from all legitimate entries after the closing date. Bunches.co.uk reserves the right to reject fraudulent entries or those not compliant with the Terms and Conditions.
  * The judge's decision is final and no correspondence will be entered into.
  * Winners will be notified by email by Tuesday 28th August 2018. If the winners do not respond, Bunches.co.uk reserves the right to forfeit the allocation of the prize.
  * The winners may not use the prize in conjunction with any other offer, promotion or prize draw.
  * The prize will be sent to the address provided by the entrant.
  * No responsibility can be accepted for entries that are lost, delayed, or which are not received for any reason.
  * The prize is subject to availability and Bunches.co.uk reserves the right to change the prize to something of a similar value without notice if circumstances beyond our control require it to do so. This also applies to prizes being provided by a third party.
  * The winners may be asked to participate in Bunches.co.uk post-promotion publicity.
  * The promoter is Bunches Florapost, 19 Hazelford Way, Newstead Village, Nottinghamshire, NG15 0DQ. Please do not send entries to this address.
  * Your personal data will be treated in confidence by Bunches Florapost Ltd and will not be disclosed to any other parties for their marketing purposes.
  * All entry instructions form part of these terms and conditions. By entering this promotion, all participants will be deemed to have accepted and be bound by them.
  * Terms & Conditions correct as of 12th July 2018.

##### Monday Email Prize Draw

  * Prize draw closes at midnight on the Sunday following the Monday email.
  * Prize: 5 winners will be selected at random from the entries and will receive the winning bouquet as stated in the email. Each prize will be sent separately. No cash alternative available and the prize is non-transferable.
  * Competitions and prize draws are open to everyone aged 18 and over (excluding employees of Bunches Florapost Ltd their families or anyone else associated with the promotion).
  * Only one entry per person. Entries made on behalf of another person will not be accepted and joint submissions are not allowed.
  * Prize can only be delivered to addresses within the UK.
  * The winners will be chosen randomly from all legitimate entries after the closing date. Bunches.co.uk reserves the right to reject fraudulent entries or those not compliant with the Terms and Conditions.
  * The judge's decision is final and no correspondence will be entered into.
  * Winners will be notified by email on the following Monday. If the winners do not respond, Bunches.co.uk reserves the right to forfeit the allocation of the prize.
  * The winners may not use the prize in conjunction with any other offer, promotion or prize draw.
  * The prize will be sent to the address provided by the entrant.
  * No responsibility can be accepted for entries that are lost, delayed, or which are not received for any reason.
  * The prize is subject to availability and Bunches.co.uk reserves the right to change the prize to something of a similar value without notice if circumstances beyond our control require it to do so. This also applies to prizes being provided by a third party.
  * The winners may be asked to participate in Bunches.co.uk post-promotion publicity.
  * The promoter is Bunches Florapost, 19 Hazelford Way, Newstead Village, Nottinghamshire, NG15 0DQ. Please do not send entries to this address.
  * Your personal data will be treated in confidence by Bunches Florapost Ltd and will not be disclosed to any other parties for their marketing purposes.
  * All entry instructions form part of these terms and conditions. By entering this promotion, all participants will be deemed to have accepted and be bound by them.
  * Terms & Conditions correct as of 15th August 2018.

  *[VAT]: Value Added Tax
